Guide to the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Photograph Collection ALBA.PHOTO.015
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
- Series I: Photographs, 1930s-1990s.
  - Subseries I:C: Subjects, General
    - Madrid: (Hans Amlie, John T. Bernard, Congressmen Jerry O'Connell, visiting children's colonies/schools, Madrid), 1937 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Madrid: Architecture before, during, and after Bombing, ca. [Aug 1937] (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Madrid: Elias Begelman (aka Biegleman); David Engels, and Charles Nusser, Jun 1937 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Map and Banner "Taken by Lincoln Washington Brigade Dec 1937" (men point to large wall map of Spain), [1938-1939?] (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Marca ( Sanidad chow line, Jul 1938); ( Transmiciones kitchen, Jun 1938) (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - McCarran Bill: "The Reaper" Political Cartoon (hand drawn), undated (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Medical Facilities, Surgery, and Treatment (general,15 photos); Norman Duncan and Bob Raven, ca.1936-1938 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Medical Personnel: (Rose Abramson; Dr. Richard Chodoff, Ruth Wilson Epstein, Dr. Marcus Fried, Dr. Barney Malbin, Carol Miller, Alba Novac, Gus Towsen, Esther Silverstein, Dr. Zachary Stadt, Helen Williams, and Dr. Lewis Zanderer); (Dr. Lewis Cohen, Eugenia Grunsky, Dr. Leonard Larsen, Grace Margolis, Dr. Frances Vanzant, and Harry Wilkes), ca.1936-1939 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Mondejar: Rifle Range, Dec 1937 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Murcia: Hospital and Hospital Sponsored Fiesta (includes group of patients and nurse, "Injured English Soldier" and crowd photos), ca.1936-1939 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Navy: "Members of Spanish Republican Naval Forces" (seven sailors behind sand bags with cannon; large format), ca.1936-1939 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - New York: Anniversary of World War I Demonstration, Apr 6, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - New York: Anti-Franco Pickets outside Spanish Consulate (10 photos), Mar 1946, Jul 1946 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - New York: Group of Organizations Waiting to Greet 149 Volunteers Arriving on SS Paris, Dec 1938 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - New York: Lincoln Brigade Demonstration (10 photos), May 17, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - New York: Lincoln Brigade, May Day Parades, 1937-1938, 1940-1941, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - New York: Lincoln Brigade, Picket "Free All Political Prisoners in Franco Jails" (in rain at night), [1960s?] (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - New York: Lincoln Brigade, Times Square Anti-Franco March (6 photos), Nov 1947 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - New York: Madison Square Park Rally against Fascism, including American Committee for Spanish Freedom Rally (7 photos), Apr 1946 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - New York: Parade, Working Class Supporters of Peace, undated (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - New York: Pickets "Italian Invaders Must Get Out of Spain!", 1939 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - New York: "Pickets outside Spain Office" (2 photos), ca.1937-1945 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - New York: Pickets at Spanish Tourist Office (including burning effigy and arrests) (6 photos), Jan 30, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - New York: Pickets, Waldorf Astoria, Oct 1946 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - New York: Tag Day, Anti-Franco Sound Truck (2 photos), May 1946 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - New York: Tag Day, Women Collecting Money for Spanish Republican Refugees Fund (2 photos), Nov 1947 (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - New York: "UN Delegation, W. 57th St", Jun 1946 (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - New York: Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Office Staff, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - New York: Veterans gather by Poliacoff's Kosher Restaurant, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - New York: Waterfront, Maritime Unions Picket Spanish Ship " SS Marques de Camillas" and Committee to Win the Peace (4 photos, one featuring Abbot Simon and Eugene Connolly), Aug 1946-Oct 1946 (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - Orihuela (Ernest Amatniek, Jackie Freeman, Joe Max Hamberger, Al Morgan-Shimer, Clarence Prince, William Crane Van Felix, and Jaiver Yates, Dec 1937-Jan 1938); (group on terrace, [1936]), ca.1936-1939 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Prisoners: (Charles Barr, Homer Bates Chase, Morris Conway, Norman Kreisler Dorland, Fritz; unidentified man, after release, [1938], 3 different photos); (Dinner at Commodore Hotel to Welcome 14 Americans Released from Prison Camp, Oct 1938, 2 photos); (Louis Noah Ornitz, and Maurice Conway POW returning on SS Queen Mary with Charles Barr interviewed by Frankie Basch of station WMCA, Oct 18, 1938, 2 photos); (parade to honor returning prisoners, including $150,000 Banner and children's marching band, Oct 1938, 3 photos); ("Reception at pier to greet 14 released fascist prisoners arrived Queen Mary" New York, Oct 18, 1938), undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Propaganda: (Anti-Fascist "Book" in street with Spanish pedestrians, [1936-1940s?] 2 photos); ("Citizens Traverse Propaganda-Laden Streets in Spain"); (Lone Soldier); (letter referring to aerial bombardment, Nov 19, 1936); (Popular Front propaganda surrounding doorways " El Glorioso Ejercito" ); (Poster, at a distance, blurred); (soldier with tasseled hat embraces dark-haired beauty); (Spanish Shop Workers' Union lists volunteers "100.000 Voluntaris el CA.A.D.CA.I. Sol 5.000 Voluntaris"); (two female comrades, arm in arm); ("Typical Soldier" pulling grenade pin), ca.1936-1939 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Quinto: Fascist Fortification Captured and Used as General Staff Headquarters, Aug 1937 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Quinto: Prisoners (2 photos), undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Renau, Josep: Photographs of Paintings (6 photos), 1938 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Republican Troops: Advancing at Teruel Front (2 photos), Jan 1938 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Return of the Lincoln Brigade Parade ("Ben Angel," 7 different photos), [Dec] 1938 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Seventy-fourth Brigade: Three Members at Kilo 15, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Shipboard: Bill Allander, Jim Bourne, Roy Braden, Ralph Diggers, George Foucek, James Fowler, Oiva Halonen, Ernie Kolowski, Clement Markert, Tom Norton, Saul Shapiro, and Earl Wildman, [1938] (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Shipboard: Dave Altman, Vernon Bown, William Faber, Frank Ferrero, Clarence Forester, Kenneth Forester, John Jacques, William Ketola, Jack Lane, Albert James Pitt, Ragnar Pylkki, John W. Snyder, Harold Stone, Don Thayer, Larry Wendorf, and Sam Wren, [1938] (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Shipboard: Thomas Callaghan, Steve Domas, Ben Findley, Ben Goldstein, George Hagertie, George Henry, Louis Knepp, John Kohler, Paul Layton, Jeff Weiderman, [1938] (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Shipboard: Frank Arvola, Stephen Bajza, John Baker, Arthur Capman, Bob Cummins, Hugo Heinrich, Waino Hofstrom, John Kesserling, Alex Lewandowski, Marion Noble, Tersil Obrist, Bob Reed, John Rosen, Elman Service, John Small, and Nathan Weisenfeld, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Shipboard: Milton Cohen, Frank Cone, Easey Goldstein, Bernie Havens, Jack Hartzman, Nick Krist, Edward Paleza, John Panscik, William Oderaka, Dan Taylor, Godfrey Thompson, Guy Thorpe, Joe Zawadowsky, and Lou Zivin, [1938] (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Shipboard: Walter Cobbs, James Cox, Faray Dukes, Ken Graeber, Wesley Howard, Ben Kosinoff, Len Levenson, Randolph Lock, Norm Osborne, and Joyce MacCool, [1938] (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Shipboard: Joe Appel, Hilda Bell, Luba Briska, Arnold Bennet Donowa, Ruth Epstein, Albin Ragowski, and unidentified others (aboard S. S. President Harding returning from Spain, Dec 31, 1938) (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Shipboard: Isodor (Frank) Barcena, (Large group photo of Lincoln Battalion, on board S. S. President Harding, includes copy of enclosure letter to "Nelson" from Barcena), undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Shipboard: Dr. Arnold Bennet Donowa with Albin Ragner (Ragowski) and group on Board SS President Harding, Dec 31, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Shipboard: POWs returning aboard the S.S. President Harding before the Statue of Liberty, Ray Anderson, Charles Hall, unidentified, George Severdia, Joseph Radacoy, Fred Stanley, Joseph Grigas, Frank Grodsky, William Graver, Fred Borer, Max Parker, John Hollis Jenkins, Claude Pringle, Martin Maki, Henry Megquier, John Piekarski, Charles Keith, Sidney Rosenblatt, Eugene Debs Poling, Howard Earl, Edward Johnson, Carl Geiser, Otto Lemke, Sam Koneski, John Higgins, Ed Hodge, John Panaszewicz, Walter Manning, Tom Brown, May 6, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Shipboard: Al Bires, Leroy Collins, Socrates Economides, Early Payne, Blackie Sandborn, Max Schartzberg, Marty Stramek, and Alvin Van Arsdale (returning vets at New York docks receiving leis from unidentified women), Aug 4, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Shipboard: Samuel Gonshak, David Watron Lippert, Joh Rody, Louis Secundy, Jesse Wallach, [1938?] (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Shipboard: Henry Fuller, Reverend Al Fuller ("of Boston"), Leonard Grumet, Steve Levine, Jack Miller, and Anton Ulvi, Aug 4, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Shipboard: International Brigade Members Return from Spain on the "Champlain" via Le Havre, Spring 1938 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Shipboard: International Brigade Members (3 men, one smiling in beret), undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Shipboard: "Lincoln 15 Brigade" Return to New York on the "Manhattan", Spring 1938 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Shipboard: Lawrence Lustgarten, in group photo with three unidentified men on SS. Ausonia, "coming home"), [1938] (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Shipboard: Arthur Munday, Sam Nahman [aka Manny Harriman], Hank Ruben, Milton Wolff, and unidentified others ( SS. Ansonia, Dec 20, 1938) (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Shipboard: 13 Released prisoners, hats in the Air (includes Charles Barr, and Maurice Conway, [aka Michael Morris or Maurice Cohen]), Oct 1938 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Shipboard: S. S. Washington, Apr 1939 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Shipboard: Two Unidentified Men (backs to camera) on deck, ca.1936-1939 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Siqueiros, David Alfaro: Photograph of Painting ("Lincoln y Marti"), undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Soldiers: Unidentified Groups (24 photos), ca.1936-1939 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Soldiers: Unidentified Individuals (7 photos), ca.1936-1939 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Soldiers: Unidentified Pairs (7 photos), ca.1936-1939 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Spanish Groups: (Dancing); (Waiting to Vote); (Soldiers with Women and Children); etc., ca.1936-1939 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Spanish Women and Children: (Women at Work); (Orphan Boy in Madrid); (Parade); etc., ca.1936-1939 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Teruel: (Architecture after Bombing, 10 photos); (Bishop's House); (General Juan Hernandez Saravia with the Minister of National Defense at the front); (Soldier in front of intact apartment buildings), Jan 1938 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Tinell Station: "Post with German Sign" (Soldier seated at his post on left), ca.1936-1939 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Toney, Anthony: Photographs of Paintings ("Americans in Spain" and "International Solidarity"), undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Twelfth Battalion: Smiling Soldier with Machine Gun (2 photos), ca.1936-1939 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Twelth Regiment de Tren: James Walker "Mac" Benet, Carol "Kibby" Goodman, Veikko Oliver Lindfors, Rudolph Valuch, [Henry Wileman], and unidentified, Jun 18, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Valencia: Group of Political Prisoners at Concert (2 photos), [1943] (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Valverde: Mackenzie-Papineau Group, Mar 1938 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Wall Newspapers, Including " Unidad"; " Nuestrofuente, Victoria", ca.1938 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Washington Battalion: Addressed by Officers (10 photos), ca.1936 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Washington Battalion: After First Meeting (group, candid), 1936 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Washington Battalion: Playing Ping-Pong (5 photos), ca.1936 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Washington Battalion: Wall Newspaper, ca.1936 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Washington, DC: Demonstration against Middle East Policy, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Washington, DC: IUC-CIO Anti-Franco Pickets (4 photos), 1946 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Washington, DC: Lift the Embargo Conference (Milton Wolff, Ruth Davidow, Evelyn Rahman, Luis Villaplana on steps); (Stage); (Crowd) (3 photos), Jan 9, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Washington DC: Rally against U.S. Involvement in World War II, ca.1940-1941 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Watercolor Depicting Hand-to-Hand Combat (black and white print), undated (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Vietnam: VALB Demonstration, Washington, DC (7 photos), Oct 21, [1967] (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Vietnam: VALB "Peace Parade," New York (3 photos), Apr 1969 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Subseries I:D: Monuments, Memorials, Celebrations, and Reunions
    - Friends of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (FALB), 1st Annual Celebration (Hippodrome): (George Brodsky holding receipts); (Leif Erikson and Frances Farmer, perform); (Morris Carnovsky, of Group Theatre performing); (Victor Chenkin, sings); ("Crowd Goes Wild"); (Duke Ellington); (Fred Keating); ("Night of the Stars" ); ("Vast multitudes await program" ); (Joe Whelan, Sam Bard, Phil Bard, Grace Allen, Jack Miller); (Gerry Weinberg, Steve Toplianos, and others), Apr 1938 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Memorial: Anti-Fascist Memorial, Italy (6 photos), [1995] (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Memorial: Art Work (9 contact sheets); (1 photo), undated (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Memorial: Austrian Veterans (6 photos), [1990s?] (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Memorial: Commemorative Plate (photo and correspondence), 1987 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Memorial: "David and Goliath" Statue, Barcelona (4 photos), 1998 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Ross, Adolph: Project Display for New York Luncheon, undated (Box 5, Folder 41a)
    - "To Our Fallen Comrades Our Victory Is Your Vengeance," Mark Rauchwald's Lettering (3 photos), Jun 1937 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - U.S.A.F. Cemetery Lette P.I. Gate, ca.1930s-1940s (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB) Celebration (via negative), 1957 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - VALB Christmas Party (Norman Nathan Berkowitz, dressed as Santa Claus with children; 12 photos); (Milton Wolff, with Berkowitz and unidentified man) (15 photos), Dec 1941 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - VALB Dinner, New York, May 1946 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - VALB Events at Colleges and Universities (6 photos), 1973-1994 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - VALB First National Convention: Washington, DC (5 photos); (John Perrone, Douglas Roach, and Hy Stone), Feb 12, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - VALB Monument Dedication: Madison, WI (includes photos of monument, crowds, local political figures and a group photo of Vern Bown, Moe Fishman, Clarence Forester, Carl Geiser, Charles Hall, Arthur Harrison, Aaron Hilkevitch, Clarence Kailin, and David Smith) (11 photos), Oct 31, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - VALB National Conference and Dinner 1977: New York (includes photos of Nils Waldemar Berg, Jack Bjoze, Paul Arthur Burns, Milton Cohen, Gary Cook, Tony Albert DeMaio, Harry Fisher, Moe Fishman [aka Moses Fishman], Ed Flaherty, Lester Gittelson, Louis Gnepp, Oiva Halonen, Oscar Henry Hunter, Jim Persoff [aka Jacob], Theodore Samuel Schneider, Saul Meyer Shapiro, "Doc" John Leopold Simon, Randall B. Smith[aka Pete], Robert Steck, William Susman, Hy Wallach, and Milton Wolff) (20 photos), Feb 1, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - VALB Reunion: New York, Manhattan Center (veterans gambling); (David Engels, Harold Smith, and others), Jun 25, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - VALB Reunion/Visit: German Democratic Republic (Including "1936-1966 Solidaridad Pasaremos" Stage and Crowd, 2 photos); (Evelyn Hutchins and Herman Rosenstein, Recipients of the Hans Beimler Medal, caption describing event); (Evelyn Hutchins and others) (21 photos), Jul 15, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - VALB Reunion: Includes Sarah Cunningham, Moe Fishman, and Steve Nelson, May 14, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - VALB Reunion: (16 contact sheets), 1986 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - VALB Reunion: San Francisco Bay Area (Including Ronnie Gilbert, Bill Klovok, Gene LaRoque, Steve Nelson, Leonard Olson, Ed Roberts, Alfred Tanz, Alice Walker) (20 photos), Feb 26, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - VALB Reunion: New York (Including Goldring, Benjamin and LaRoque, Gene) (23 photos), Apr 26, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - VALB Reunion: New York (26 photos), 1991 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - VALB Reunion (2 photos), 1992 (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - VALB Reunion: New York (Including Cavanaugh, John; Cullinen, George Ambrose Jr., Wolff, Milton and a veteran named "Gideon" (caption: "27 of 110 surviving attended event") (10 photos), Apr 30, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - VALB Reunion/Trips: China, Nicaragua, Hawaii (15 photos), 1974, 1989, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - VALB Reunion/Twenty-fifth Anniversary Celebration (crowd photo with stage and "25 Anniversary" sign); (Pete Seeger singing), 1962 (Box 5, Folder 61)
- Series II: Negatives, Undated.
  - 204 Negatives, undated (Box 6)
- Series III: Slides, 1974.
  - VALB Trip to China (8 color slides), 1974 (Box 6)
- Series IV: Unprocessed Photographs.
  - Subseries IV:A: Individuals
    - Amery, Al (Box 7)
    - Bates, Ralph (Box 7)
    - Bebler, Ales (Box 7)
    - Borer, Wayland, with Card (Box 7)
    - Caldarella, Mike (separated from the Sidney Kaufman Papers) (Box 7)
    - Camacho, Marcelino (Box 7)
    - Carlson, Evans (Box 7)
    - Carlson, Evans F. (U.S. Marine Corp.) (Box 7)
    - Casals, Pablo (Box 7)
    - Cohen, Al (Box 7)
    - Copic, --, Major (Box 7)
    - Dunbar, Malcolm (Box 7)
    - Egg-Benes, Maria (Box 7)
    - Feldt Orrin: 2 Photos, One group with Family (Box 7)
    - Finkle, Alex (Box 7)
    - [Fishman, Moe] (Box 7)
    - Fishman, Morris (Box 7)
    - Frankel, Irving (Dec 1982) (Box 7)
    - Garland, Walter (Lieutenant) (Box 7)
    - Gross, Nathan E. (Box 7)
    - Hamilton, Tyler (Box 7)
    - Hargrave, Roger (Box 7)
    - Harris, Abe (Albert Lyonel) and Negatives (Box 7)
    - Hasset, James Patrick (Box 7)
    - Hemingway, Ernest (Box 7)
    - [Himmelfarb, Victor?] (Box 7)
    - Hovan, John (Box 7)
    - Hughes, Langston (Box 7)
    - Hughes, Langston (one photo with Ed Rolfe) (Box 7)
    - Hutchins, Evelyn: Photos (sent by Peter Goodman to the Bay Area Post, VALB) (Box 7)
    - Hutchins, Evelyn: Portrait in front of truck (Box 7)
    - Ibarruri, Dolores (Box 7)
    - Ibarruri, Dolores (1980s) (Box 7)
    - Ibarruri, Dolores: Post-SCW (Box 7)
    - Jaffee, Bernard ("Plea For Life" Rally) (Box 7)
    - Kailin, Clarence: Portrait (Box 7)
    - Kee, Salaria (aka Salaria Kea) (Box 7)
    - Keen, Harry (Box 7)
    - Kelly, Michael (Box 7)
    - Kowolski, Walter (Box 7)
    - Land, Sanford (Box 7)
    - Lardner, Jim (Box 7)
    - Levine, Sydney (Box 7)
    - Littleton, Edward (Box 7)
    - Lossowski, Vincent - 1983 Portrait (Box 7)
    - MacLeod, Donald - SF Post 1979 (Box 7)
    - Maier, Joe (Box 7)
    - Merriman, Marian: Barcelona and Gandesa and Negatives, Aug 27 - Sep 1, 1982 (Box 7)
    - Merriman, Marian: trip to Leningrad and Negatives, Sep 11 - 15, 1982 (Box 7)
    - Miaja, Jose (General) (Box 7)
    - Miaja, Jose (General): Portrait (Box 7)
    - Murra, John V.: Photographs and Negatives (Box 7)
    - Myers, [Frederick N. "Blackie"?] (Box 7)
    - Negrin, Juan: Speech and Dan Kruzman (Negative) (Box 7)
    - Patterson, [Harry Benjamin?] (Box 7)
    - Pepper, Claude D. (Senator) (Box 7)
    - Powell, [--?] (Box 7)
    - Ragner, Albin [and wife?] (Box 7)
    - Rauschwald, Mark Benjamin (Box 7)
    - Rautbort, Anthony [of Milwaukee] (Box 7)
    - Roach, Douglas (Box 7)
    - Romero, Ernie (Box 7)
    - Rubin, Hank: Codorniu San Sadorni de Noya (Barcelona) (Box 7)
    - Sats, John (Box 7)
    - Sabath, A. J., Honorable (Box 7)
    - Schutt, William (Box 7)
    - Shapiro, Anthony (Box 7)
    - Simon, -- (from Ernie Romero) (Box 7)
    - Smith, Harold (John Oliver High School May 4, 1972) (Box 7)
    - Smith, Randall B. "Pete" (Box 7)
    - Soule Echeveria, Carlos (Box 7)
    - Stone, Joe (Hershkowitz) - Photo/Postcard (Box 7)
    - Susman, Helen - Photo of Unidentified Soldiers (Box 7)
    - Swierczewski, Karol (aka General Walter) (Box 7)
    - Thornton, Mark (Box 7)
    - Todorovich, Alex (Box 7)
    - del Vayo, Alvarez (Box 7)
    - Unidentified Individual (Box 7)
    - Unidentified Individual (Box 7)
    - Unidentified Individual (Box 7)
    - Unidentified Individual (Box 7)
    - Unidentified Individual (Box 7)
    - Unidentified Individuals (Box 7)
    - Unidentified Individual: [Girol?] (Box 7)
    - Unidentified Individual (V-315) (Box 7)
    - Unidentified Individual (V-317) (Box 7)
    - Unidentified Individual (V-318) (Box 7)
    - Unidentified Individual (V-319) (Box 7)
    - Unidentified Individual (V-320) (Box 7)
    - Unidentified Individual (V-332) (Box 7)
    - Unidentified Individuals: [meeting?] and Negatives (from Sidney Harris to Abe Smorodin) (Box 7)
    - Unidentified Individual: Playing Banjo (Box 7)
    - Unidentified Individual Portrait (Box 7)
    - Unidentified Individual Portraits (Box 7)
    - Unidentified Individual Portraits (Box 7)
    - Unidentified Individual Without Shirt (Box 7)
    - Unknown Individuals: Young Girl and Two Unidentified Men (from Martha Swatosch Collection) (Box 7)
    - Vinovich, George L. and wife (Box 7)
    - Watt, George (Box 7)
    - Whelan, Joe: [Jarama?] (Box 7)
    - Wilkes, Harry (Box 7)
    - Yates, James (May 1990) (Box 7)
  - Subseries IV:B: Individuals in Groups
    - Barsky, Edward K., [two unidentified individuals] (Box 7)
    - Amlie, Hans; Irving Fajans, Hy Stone, Victor Dominguez, Dan Fitzgerald, Dave White, John Perrone, Bob Raven (Box 7)
    - Asner, Ed; Dellums, Ronald V. (Box 7)
    - Bailey, Bill and others (Box 7)
    - Barlow and Shean (Box 7)
    - Barr, Charles; Maurice Conway and Unidentified (Box 7)
    - Berkowitz, Norman; Bill Frame, [unknown], Ed Lending, Dr. Mark Strauss (Box 7)
    - Bernie, Irving; [Mynon, Damion?] and two unidentified men (Box 7)
    - Bevet, Stephen Vincent; Charles Barr, Norman Darl (two fascist prisoners) (Oct 18, 1938) (Box 7)
    - Bre, Fanny with two Spanish Comrades (Murcia, 1937) (Box 7)
    - Browder, Earl; Robert Minor (Box 7)
    - Caballero, Largo (Box 7)
    - Doyle, Robert (with Jane and Maria to Albacete) (Box 7)
    - De Soto, Dr. L, [two unidentified] (Box 7)
    - Dwyer, Edythe - American Hospital, Villa Paz and convalescents (Box 7)
    - Eloesser, Leo Dr.; Manuel, Cleo Duncan, Pelegrini, Alice Wagnon, Asst. Dr. (Mataro) (Box 7)
    - Faber, Jake; John Bolmarcich (Box 7)
    - Feingersh, Frank; Bill Bais; James Yates; Joe Prill (Return to U.S. from Spain) (Box 7)
    - Flanagan, Terry - XV Brigade (Box 7)
    - Ford, James; Bates Britan, Two CPers from Spain, Robert Minor, [CPUSA?], Eddie White (Box 7)
    - Franco, Francisco; Adolph Hitler (Box 7)
    - Garland, Walter (Box 7)
    - Golding, Wellman (photo by Bob Coane) (Box 7)
    - Gordon, Butch; Ted Lewis, Packy Hassett, Hans Frank Madigan, Butch Logan, Brownie (dog) (Box 7)
    - Grunsberg (Polish); Ed Lending, Jim Persoff, Conlon Nancarrow (Box 7)
    - Hutchins, Evelyn, F. Martin, Toby Jensky, H. Freeman, B. Benson, S. Kea, and two unidentified men (Box 7)
    - Ibarruri, Dolores (Pasionaria), Comorera, Nelken M. (Cortes en Monserrat) (Box 7)
    - Imbert, Lena with Military Secretary of JSU de C (Box 7)
    - J. B. B. Family Photo (Box 7)
    - Jordan, June; Barbara Lubin, Ronald V. Dellums (Box 7)
    - Johnson, Saks, Avyers, Dorland, Conard, Rutherford, Keith, Staldaen (Box 7)
    - Kaufman, [Jane?] and others (April 1973) (Box 7)
    - Knowles, Leigh; Hank Rubin (Box 7)
    - Kolowski, Walter, [two unidentified men] (Box 7)
    - Ibarruri, Dolores (Box 7)
    - Ibarruri, Dolores (Box 7)
    - Lanmines (Chile), Staling (Rochester), Luna (Philipines), [unknown from Santiago, Cuba], Jach Shirai (U.S. Japanese) (Box 7)